# **JULIAN SOSA**

## UI / FRONTEND DEVELOPER

EMAIL: HiJulianSosa@gmail.com WEBSITE: hackerrank.com/hijuliancode PHONE: +57 3234957933

TWITTER: hijuliansosa LINKEDIN: /in/hijuliansosa GITHUB: hijuliancode

SUMMARY

I'm a Frontend Developer with 5 years of experience building scalable web applications with state of the art technology. I have skills in frontend and user interface design, research and attention to detail. I'm constantly challenging myself to learn new technologies and skills.

**SKILLS** 

JavaScript, ReactJS, Angular, AngularJS, jQuery, HTML, CSS, BEM, Bootstrap, Progressive Enhancement, Photoshop, Sass-Less-Stylus, SketchApp3, Git, UI Design, Gulp, Responsive Web Design, Terminal, Flexbox, Grid, AdobeXD, Figma Design, Self Learning, MongoDB, NodeJS API Rest

## **EMPLOYMENT**

### Webcreek LLC, UI Developer / Front End Stylist, Medellin - Colombia

Mar. 2019 - Feb. 2020

- Develop applications using modern front-end frameworks and back-end frameworks such as ES6, Angular, React, Ionic, Sass. Bootstrap, webpack.
- Define Frontend technology stack strategy and vision for websites, mobile applications and other interactive digital experiences.
- · Design and Develop complex software applications, Wireframing, Prototyping and Coding.

#### Lenspire, FrontEnd Web Engineer, USA - Remote Job

Dec. 2018 - Apr. 2019

- Built and optimized web components with AngularJS
- Gulp, Sass, Git, Javascript, AngularJS, Sketch, Photoshop.
- Coded landing pages
- Implemented HTML and CSS of Web Applications
- · Design and Develop complex software applications, Wireframing, Prototyping and Coding.

## Barista Ventures, Front end web developer, Medellín - Remote Job - Colombia May 2015 - Dec. 2018

- · Built and optimized web components with AngularJS and ReactJS
- Gulp, Sass, SemanticUI, Git, Javascript, AngularJS, ReactJS, Redux, Sketch, Photoshop.
- · Designed and coded landing pages
- Improved HTML and CSS code by deleting unnecessary code
- Improved web-fonts implementation
- · Participated on the design process of mobile applications
- Used Sketch and Photoshop to design app views
- Wrote application specs

#### XumaK, LLC, Front end web developer, Medellín - Colombia

Jan. 2015 - Apr. 2015

- Optimized code on web apps
- Refactored HTML and CSS code
- Reviewed HTML and CSS to delete unnecessary code
- · Javascript development

## Not The Same, Front end web developer, Bogotá - Colombia

Sept. 2013 - Jan. 2015

- · Landing Pages and Web pages development from Scratch, with and without frameworks
- Email & Newsletter Development, Support of different email platforms

## **EDUCATION**

#### Make it Real Camp

Front end developer 2017

Bootcamp specialized in JavaScript, Angular, ReactJS, Redux, Firebase, JQuery, Ajax and Git, HTML and CSS3.

#### **SENA**

Programación de Software 2013

Government institution. I Acquired JavaScript, Algorithms, PHP, HTML5 and CSS skills.

# VOLUNTEERING

#### Soldier on Colombian National Army

Nov. 2009 - Nov. 2011

- Passion for my work
- Work under pressure.
- Handle positions of trust.
- Organization/Management teams.
- Training should be so strong that the war/practice is a rest.